#### Contact

sgroves45@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/susan-groves-2ab14414 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills
CCRN
ACLS
Medical/Surgical

# Susan Groves

Staff RN at Lee Health

Cape Coral, Florida

### Summary

I have a vast amount of experience as a bedside nurse. Bedside nurses provide education to patients, families, new nurses, and nursing students. After obtaining my Master's degree in Nursing Education, I feel I am better qualified to provide education to anyone seeking to learn or needing to learn. My ultimate objective has always been to teach. I enjoy mentoring new nurses and nursing students. I also enjoy helping to ensure that my practice is up-todate with evidence-based guidelines. I worked for nearly 2 years as a Clinical Nurse Educator in a busy surgical intensive care unit. There I learned so much about the application of educational concepts in clinical practice, and, just as I did when I was a bedside nurse, I learn something new every day. As a Continuing Education Specialist, I was involved with on-boarding new employees. I worked to develop training programs when an educational need is identified. I help with educational conferences, and also coordinate all the CPR training within the institution. I truly enjoyed my work! Now I am honored to have the opportunity to once again practice bedside nursing in a progressive ICU. I am looking forward to learning new things and working with a diverse group of nurses. I see a lot of personal growth ahead and I'm excited about that prospect.

## Experience

Lee Health

1 year 3 months

Staff RN

April 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Cape Coral, Florida

RN

April 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Cape Coral, Florida

I am returning to my roots. I have always loved taking care of critically ill patients and now I have an opportunity to do so again with my added educational skills. I'm excited about this new chapter in my life and looking forward to learning new things.

North Mississippi Health Services
Continuing Education Specialist
June 2017 - March 2019 (1 year 10 months)
Tupelo, MS

What an honor to work with this amazing group of people! I learned so much about on-boarding new employees, creating effective educational programs, and presenting programs. This was my dream job. I had to leave due to relocating, but I wish I could have taken them with me!

North Mississippi Medical Center Clinical Nurse Educator October 2015 - June 2017 (1 year 9 months) Tupelo, MS

I am privileged to work with new nurses and nurses who have transferred from other areas as they transition to working with critically ill patients.

#### **NMMC**

RN

December 1995 - October 2015 (19 years 11 months)

Staff nurse in critical care

Gilmore Memorial Hospital

RN

September 1985 - November 1995 (10 years 3 months)

Staff nurse in float pool with ICU,ER, telemetry, med-surg, post-partum, pediatrics.

Head Nurse of 9 bed ICU.

### Education

South University Online

Master of Science in Nursing, Nursing Education · (2011 - 2015)

Itawamba Community College

Associates Degree, Nursing · (1988 - 1989)